<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link href="https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/index.rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <title>Observations</title>
    <link>https://natureshare.org/items?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Findex.json</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 leuba</copyright>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 11:31:33 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>jsonfeed-to-rss 3.0.3 (https://github.com/bcomnes/jsonfeed-to-rss#readme)</generator>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enchocrates glaucopis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2019%2F5d9c8c02cad3ebb2a1000247.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A pale moth with purple tinged wings and fringed trailing margins. Wingspan could have been about 10 to 12 mm.Each fore wing had a smudged dark patch in the middle of the inner margin which at rest formed a dark circle. On each wing was also a small dark, slightly posterior to the dark patch. Antennae were swept back. The labial palps appeared to form a "snout" with a short stiff bristle on either side at the tip.&#xD;
Seen under a bright garden light on a warm night.</description>
      <category>id~Enchocrates glaucopis</category>
      <category>tag~adult-moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2019/5d9c8c02cad3ebb2a1000247.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 13:15:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2019%2F5c517ac33abbd687fb000126.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These were small wrinkled 5 mm wide balls at the end of stems of a casuarina tree. At least one small branch had several of these with holes ( parasitoid ?). Most were dry but a single fresh green gall on the same branch had a knobbly surface. When dissected the gall showed several thick-walled locules.&#xD;
These look similar to galls seen on C.glauca induced by the gall wasp Selitrichodes.  I would greatly appreciate help with identifying the gall inducer and the Casuarina species. Thanks.</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2019/5c517ac33abbd687fb000126.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 10:21:55 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endoxyla magnifica</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2019%2F5c3abe3d3abbd6e68200000f.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A large grey female Cossid with a wing span of about 175 mm. It made a crash landing and thrashed &amp; skidded about on its back rubbing-off most of its scales on the thorax and wings. It finally calmed down when offered a large piece of eucalyptus bark. There were no significant patterns on wings or thorax on the grey upper side. The undersides of the wings were a deep pinkish-brown with a pale edging to the inner margin of the fore wings. The abdomen was thick and densely covered with brown tinged setae dorsally and was white on the ventral side.&#xD;
Attracted to bright lights on building near a National Park.</description>
      <category>id~Endoxyla magnifica</category>
      <category>tag~moth-grey</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2019/5c3abe3d3abbd6e68200000f.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 04:27:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tinzeda sororoides</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2019%2F5c3a973b3abbd6664b0006ab.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A slender green katydid with a white stripe running along the midline and lateral aspect of the thorax. Each fore wing shows strong white stripes with a red lower margin, one running along the middle and the other, along the outer edge of the wing. Long antennae were a pale yellow.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights - warm night.</description>
      <category>id~Tinzeda sororoides</category>
      <category>tag~katydid</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2019/5c3a973b3abbd6664b0006ab.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 01:41:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arrade leucocosmalis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2019%2F5c34085b3abbd6034c00010b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>An attractive pale brown moth with a wing span of about 20 mm. The fore wings had diffuse dark brown patches with two thin white lines in the mid-wing region and a line in the submarginal area curving towards the trailing margin and ending in a small white spot. The costa near the trailing margin also showed small white specks. Apices were pale. &#xD;
The thorax showed a flash of white and this aligned with a single patch of white along the inner margin of each forewing, evident when the wings parted (pic 2).&#xD;
Hind wings were a pale orange and appeared to have fringed margins. The dorsal aspect of the abdomen and legs were also tinged with a pale yellow.&#xD;
Very active moth. Spotted on a warm night under bright garden lights. Would greatly appreciate help with identification. Thanks.</description>
      <category>id~Arrade leucocosmalis</category>
      <category>tag~moth-brown</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2019/5c34085b3abbd6034c00010b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 02:18:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Idioses littleri</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2019%2F5c30af403abbd68eb4000290.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This small moth was about 6 mm long with pale grey blotchy wings. there were dark grey patches at the apices and mid costal region of the fore wings. The thorax sported a black tuft of short setae and posterior to this was a smaller tuft along the midline. &#xD;
Antennae were short and feathery.&#xD;
Attracted to bright lights - very warm night.</description>
      <category>id~Idioses littleri</category>
      <category>tag~moth-black-white</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2019/5c30af403abbd68eb4000290.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 13:21:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maroga melanostigma</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5c124c5d2a53d7f8c3000168.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A smooth white moth with a wing span of 40 mm, with, as the name suggests two small spots of black on the wings. Surprisingly, the underside showed orange and black banding on the dorsal side of the abdomen and a white belly. The legs were covered with short orange coloured setae. Eyes and antennae were black. labial palps were rec-curved.</description>
      <category>id~Maroga melanostigma</category>
      <category>tag~moth-white</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5c124c5d2a53d7f8c3000168.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 12:11:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5c07c8871779a4838500009b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Solitary stalked outgrowths from stems of a eucalyptus tree ( species not known) about 25 mm long and about 5 mm at the thickest part. One of them had split outer layers and a definite pointy tip. This gall was parasitised. &#xD;
There were two similar but smaller galls on other branches but these had rounded tips. The galls were all dry.</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~eucalypt-galls</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5c07c8871779a4838500009b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 12:45:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rickenella spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5b212422ed2a89785900378e.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Caps of this bright orange mushroom were no more than 10 mm with a deep central depression. Younger fruiting bodies were almost hemispherical, flattening out as the mature. Caps showed some striation and margins were wavy. &#xD;
Stipe was smooth and slightly paler than the cap.  Could not get a shot of the gills. Possibly Rickenella fibula.</description>
      <category>id~Rickenella spp.</category>
      <category>tag~fungi-orange-brown</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5b212422ed2a89785900378e.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 14:07:54 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phellodon spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5b1d2de4ed2a8978590028eb.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A leathery, thick fruiting body with frilly greyish-white margins. The centre of the caps were dark, almost black and looked silky. The largest of these caps were about 50 mm wide. &#xD;
Growing on damp sandy soil in a reserve of mixed natives.  This is possibly Phellodon niger.</description>
      <category>id~Phellodon spp.</category>
      <category>tag~black-fungi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5b1d2de4ed2a8978590028eb.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 14:08:47 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5b1be38aed2a89785900254b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>&#xD;
A robust mushroom with a purplish brown cap, about 40 mm wide. Some viscosity seen on cap which had a broad flattened umbo. The stipe was pale with blue longitudinal fibrils, widening at the base and then tapering. Gills were tan with a grey tint. Spore print tan with a hint of purple.&#xD;
Spotted growing on damp sandy soil, in leaf litter in a reserve of mixed natives.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~fungi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5b1be38aed2a89785900254b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 14:33:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cystophora torulosa</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5b13dbbaed2a897859000b47.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This attractive sea weed had a zig-zagging tough central stalk with small densely clustered bladder like blades, arising at points in the zig-zag. Some blades had a bifurcation. The whole body of the seaweed was a brownish green with dark brown tinges.&#xD;
Said to grow in the low intertidal and shallow subtidal rocky reefs with moderate wave action, to depth of 10 m. &#xD;
Spotted along the high tide mark on a sandy shore, along with other sea weeds - Western Port Bay &#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Cystophora torulosa</category>
      <category>tag~seaweed</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5b13dbbaed2a897859000b47.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 12:19:50 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gloiosaccion brownii</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5b13d8c0ed2a897859000b31.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This pale reddish brown elongated sac-like structure with a club shaped tip and narrow base is part of a red seaweed which grows in a clump, attached to the sea floor by a  discoid holdfast. The inside of the bladder appears to be filled with mucilage. This bladder was about 50 mm long.&#xD;
This seaweed can grow up to 16 cms in length. The outer walls of sacs growing in rough waters are said to be thicker than those in calm waters. The secretory cells lining the inside of the sacs produce highly viscous mucilage. &#xD;
Spotted along the high tide mark along with other sea weeds on a sandy beach - Western Port Bay. &#xD;
Occur in Seagrass beds upto a depth of 20 mts. &#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Gloiosaccion brownii</category>
      <category>tag~seaweed</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5b13d8c0ed2a897859000b31.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 12:10:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thylacodes sipho</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5b0bf964ed2a89fa060055ac.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This coiled thin shell with pale orange bands is that of a marine gastropod/snail that lives in a coiled tube. The snails resemble tube worms (polychaetes) because of the structure but are in a different family. The tube is usually cemented to other structures. Unlike other snails, this species does not have an operculum or lid.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Thylacodes sipho</category>
      <category>tag~snail</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5b0bf964ed2a89fa060055ac.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 12:49:45 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electroma papilionacea</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5b0abaa7ed2a897493000003.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A bivalve with paper-thin shells and about 40 mm wide. It had broken orange bands radiating from the umbo (where the valves are hinged). A very fragile specimen that was surprisingly intact despite being blown about in the wind. The slightly flared part of the shell near the umbo (on the Lt side in Pic 1) is called the auricle or wing, giving the species it's common name. &#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Electroma papilionacea</category>
      <category>tag~shell</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5b0abaa7ed2a897493000003.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 14:08:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goniocidaris tubaria</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5af2eb73ed2a893f5a002a65.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This slate-pencil sea urchin would have been about 50 mm across. It had probably just died and been washed ashore - still had most of its short thick primary spines and smaller needle like secondary spines. &#xD;
The primary photo is of the top side (aboral) and the second is of the underside (oral) with the mouth in the middle. Just visible in pic 4 is a triangular white tooth-like structure in the centre which is part of a complex dental apparatus called the "Aristotle's Lantern". &#xD;
The shorter spines were a deep red and the thicker ones were paler, some with deep red ridges. It is possible that a few long ones were broken at this stage.&#xD;
Spotted on the rocky ocean shore -low tide mark on the south coast. (Phillip Island)&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Goniocidaris tubaria</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5af2eb73ed2a893f5a002a65.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 12:49:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyura stolonifera</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5ae463f4ed2a891526000060.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Sea squirts/ tunicates/ascidians which appeared like clumps of collapsed "sand-crusted" sacs stuck to a sea fan. Each sac had two openings with scalloped edges - one on top and the other to the side (inhalant &amp; exhalant siphons). The sacs seemed to have a reddish tinge. The inside of each sac had organs which were red in colour with a brown segment towards the base (pics 3 &amp; 4). The organs seemed to be covered by mucilaginous substance. Commonly also called Conjevoi.&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Pyura stolonifera</category>
      <category>tag~ascidian</category>
      <category>tag~tunicate</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5ae463f4ed2a891526000060.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 12:14:51 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aulactinia veratra</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5ac1bb32ed2a8994660005f6.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>The anemone was about 50 mm with tentacles extended and floating in the water. Tentacles were numerous, translucent but dark green in colour and had pointy ends. The oral disc was covered by sand and therefore not visible. &#xD;
Where the anemones were out of water, they looked like dark clumps studded with sand grains. Partially submerged anemones (pic 3) were interesting in that the submerged part had extended tentacles and the exposed part was curled up displaying a sand encrusted column. Long striations could be seen in the retracted column which was the same colour as the tentacles.&#xD;
Spotted in rock pools - rocky intertidal zone (Cape Conran) </description>
      <category>id~Aulactinia veratra</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5ac1bb32ed2a8994660005f6.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 05:16:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhipicera (Agathorhipis) femorata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5abe0fd5ed2a896baf008a07.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A black wedge-shaped beetle about 15 mm long with white specks on elytra and dramatically flabellate antennae. Legs were a deep brown with black colouring at the femoral and tibial joint. A slightly humped scutellum and head were also black.&#xD;
Spotted on a young eucalyptus tree in a small reserve. &#xD;
The larvae are ecto-and endoparasitic on other insect larvae, possibly of cicada.&#xD;
Commonly called feather-horned beetle.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Rhipicera (Agathorhipis) femorata</category>
      <category>tag~beetle-spotted</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5abe0fd5ed2a896baf008a07.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:31:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brachidontes rostratus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5abde0deed2a89083d000069.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These mussels were about 40 mm long. The purple shells had black rims with thin curved lines. &#xD;
They were seen in clusters and were of varying sizes.&#xD;
Spotted on exposed rocks - rocky shoreline in the intertidal area ( Cape Conran, Victoria) &#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Brachidontes rostratus</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5abde0deed2a89083d000069.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 07:06:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galeolaria caespitosa</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5abddcd0ed2a891548000001.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This mass resembling worn coral was about 10 cms across. On the surface were crescent shaped structures which were the open ends of calcareous tubes constructed by tubeworms. They have clustered together and probably grown on a snail, completely enveloping it and forming a hard mass, as suggested by Audrey Falconer(Marine Research). The mass was partially covered with sand but red algae could be seen growing on the mass.&#xD;
The tubes are built by annelid fanworms from the family Serpulidae. The worms have branchial crowns in two lobes, one of them has a stalked operculum (lid). The branchial croown form the gills and also helps to capture food. &#xD;
The worm lives within the tube and retracts into the tube when in danger or when the tide is out, pulling the operculum down tight to shut the opening of the tube. A dense mass of tubes can form a microhabitat for other marine creatures. My thanks to Audrey Falconer ( Marine Research) for identifying this mass. &#xD;
Spotted in a rock pool in an intertidal zone of a rocky shoreline ( Cape Conran, Victoria). These tubeworms are seen from Southern Queensland all along the southern coast to Western Australia.</description>
      <category>id~Galeolaria caespitosa</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5abddcd0ed2a891548000001.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 06:52:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meridiastra calcar</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5abddb51ed2a89083d000065.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>An eight-armed carpet sea star with greenish grey colouring. The arms showed some red along the margins. The body pattern included small white scalloping and the central disc was a beautiful green. &#xD;
The arms were well defined ending in thick rounded tips. &#xD;
This sea star was about 50 mm across.&#xD;
Spotted in a rock pool - intertidal rocky shore (Cape Conran) facing the Bass Strait. They occur all around the Australian coast. </description>
      <category>id~Meridiastra calcar</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5abddb51ed2a89083d000065.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 06:43:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sypharochiton pelliserpentis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5abdc873ed2a896baf008930.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A mollusc with a flattened body and eight distinctive overlapping plates that protect them from predators and crashing waves. This chiton was grey-green in colour, about 63 mm x 35 mm. The girdle encircling the plates had a snake-skin like appearance giving it the common name "snakeskin chiton".&#xD;
These chitons were found along with barnacles, attached to the side of a rock in an intertidal rocky shore (Cape Conran) off the south coast of Victoria facing the Bass Strait. &#xD;
This species is said to prefer rock surfaces in the mid-tide region, rather than under rocks in lower -or sub-tidal zones. &#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Sypharochiton pelliserpentis</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5abdc873ed2a896baf008930.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 05:28:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endotricha spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a7c2c1ced2a89def7000f07.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This moth had a wing span of 20 mm. Typical to this species, it stood on it's front legs holding it's up-curved abdomen in the air with the apices of the fore wings resting on either side. &#xD;
The wings were a mix of grey and brown with thin wavy lines. The costa had white markings down the whole length.&#xD;
Spotted under bright garden light. Unsure of the ID as there are a few with varying wing patterns and colour.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Endotricha spp.</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a7c2c1ced2a89def7000f07.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 10:59:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroclathrus clathratus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a6bec91ed2a89d02a001128.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A brown algae with a thallus (body) with multiple holes of varying sizes. The algae is said to be about 10 cm in diameter. But in the one that was washed ashore it was a loose mesh like a woolen hair net. The whole mass was compressible and soft.&#xD;
Found on the inter-tidal zone off Western Port Bay (Balnarring Beach). They are said to grow in the tidal zone.&#xD;
'Hydro' = water, 'Clathrus' = mesh &#xD;
This species forms dense mats. &#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Hydroclathrus clathratus</category>
      <category>tag~seaweed</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a6bec91ed2a89d02a001128.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 03:11:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aplysia sydneyensis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a6bea57ed2a89d02a001108.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This sea slug would have been about 5 " in length. It had mottling of cream and brown. The ear-like sensory clubs or rhinophores and oral tentacle were withdrawn and the usually extended side flaps called parapodia were flipped back. The mantle and atrophied shell could be seen (pic 5) as a reddish radiating structure.&#xD;
I have the expert Mattt  Nimbs to thank for the ID. He says "Definitely Aplysia. And yes probably A sydneyensis, there is a wheel like pattern of radiating stripes on the mantle that sits over the vestigial shell: a distinguishing characteristic of sydneyensis"&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Aplysia sydneyensis</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a6bea57ed2a89d02a001108.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 03:03:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zonaria spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a6bdffced2a89d02a0010da.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small clump of brown algae (Phaeophyceae) with flat dark lower branches and twisted paler tips.&#xD;
Spotted on a tidal zone - Balnarring beach ( Westernport Bay).&#xD;
My thanks to Janine Baker for identifying the genus.  Possibly Z.spiralis </description>
      <category>id~Zonaria spp.</category>
      <category>tag~seaweed</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a6bdffced2a89d02a0010da.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 02:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thuretia quercifolia</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a6bddc7ed2a89d02a0010d3.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A dense clump of pale orange seaweed (red algae) with oak-leaf shaped fronds/thalli. &#xD;
Washed-up onto the beach off Westernport Bay (Balnarring Beach).&#xD;
This species gets it's name "quercifolia" fro the oak-shaped fronds. &#xD;
It is reported that this is a common and distinctive species found in deep waters in the rough-water coasts of southern Australia. &#xD;
My thanks to Janine Baker for the ID. &#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Thuretia quercifolia</category>
      <category>tag~seaweed</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a6bddc7ed2a89d02a0010d3.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 02:09:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a69c831ed2a89d02a0008c0.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small, very active dark beetle commonly called Water Penny from family Psephenidae had a slightly dorso-ventrally flattened body. The elytra showed two narrow bands of pale specks. The pronotum which was the same colour as the elytra had a pair of short pale streaks on either side of midline arising from the posterior margin. The lateral margins had pale flecks. The elytra stopped short of the terminal abdominal segments. Head was small with relatively large closely placed eyes. Antennae were segmented. &#xD;
Legs were thin with feeble tarsi.&#xD;
Flew in towards the garden lights on a warm night and then disappeared under some wood.&#xD;
&#xD;
( Please add Sclerocyphon sp.)</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~beetle-blackbrown</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a69c831ed2a89d02a0008c0.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 12:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a6017c4ed2a8959b50009b4.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This oecophorine moth had a white head and thorax. Wings were white with broad, dark costal margins which were broken by two oblique bands of white on either side. The body of the fore wings showed dark smudges and spots. Labial palps were re-curved. &#xD;
Wing span about 20 mms.&#xD;
Attracted to bright garden lights on a warm day. Area has tall gum trees.&#xD;
&#xD;
(Please add Palimmeces hemiphanes. Thanks.)</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~moth-white-wing-markings</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a6017c4ed2a8959b50009b4.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 03:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloroclystis filata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a60100eed2a8959b5000981.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>An attractive moth with patches of rust brown and grey on the fore wings and narrow white wavy transverse bands that dipped down at the apices. Hind wings showed thin wavy brown lines and a broader white band near the trailing margin. The under side of the silky wings were pale. Wing span about 20 mm.&#xD;
Spotted under bright garden lights.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Chloroclystis filata</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a60100eed2a8959b5000981.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 03:13:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tortricopsis pyroptis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a5614d2ed2a89d22b001518.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small attractive moth that looked almost square because of a hunched back. Satiny wings were a creamy colour deepening to a reddish-brown towards the trailing margins. Two lines of small black dots slanted downwards from the mid-costal area. &#xD;
Wing span - 20 mm.&#xD;
Drawn to bright garden lights. Mixed natives in the area.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Tortricopsis pyroptis</category>
      <category>tag~moth-small</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a5614d2ed2a89d22b001518.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 13:31:47 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dysbatus sp. (1)</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2018%2F5a5021e2ed2a89da71000107.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A moth with a wing span of about 30 mm. It was more grey than brown with the fore wings showing a central transverse band. Each fore wing had two oblique black lines, one running from wing base downwards to the inner margin and a shorter one from the apex of each fore wing running upwards.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights on a warm night in a suburban garden. Mixed native trees around. Also near a national park.&#xD;
 I am hoping the moth will return tonight so I can get a better shot/natural light.  Thanks to Cathy Powers for confirming this as Dysbatus.</description>
      <category>id~Dysbatus sp. (1)</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2018/5a5021e2ed2a89da71000107.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 01:29:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dysbatus sp. (1)</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a47687aed2a89e23c00363d.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This moth had an attractive shimmer to its grey-brown wings. The wing veins stood out and were a distinctive brown. Each fore wing had two thin transverse black lines that together formed a band when at rest. Within the band was a small black crescent shaped mark. A narrow black line traversed the thorax along the anterior edge. Underside of wings were pale with dark sooty patches nearer the trailing margins. Wing span would have been about 30 mm.&#xD;
Spotted in a suburban garden. Probably attracted to lights at night.&#xD;
Thanks to Cathy Powers for the ID.</description>
      <category>id~Dysbatus sp. (1)</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a47687aed2a89e23c00363d.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 10:43:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stereocaulon ramulosum</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a348893ed2a896e760002bc.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These attractive clumps of pale grey lichen were seen on rocks. They appeared to start of as regular clumps with soft tight branches  with minute convoluted bluish grey pads. The branches appeared to open up into long pendulous filamentous strands ending in rounded brown apothecia.&#xD;
Spotted on rocks at an altitude of 1200 mts. in a national park (Baw Baw NP)&#xD;
Wondering if this is a species of Cladonia. Any help with an ID will be greatly appreciated. Thanks.</description>
      <category>id~Stereocaulon ramulosum</category>
      <category>tag~lichen</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a348893ed2a896e760002bc.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 02:53:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Idaea philocosma</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a33b64ced2a896262001a71.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This slightly pearly, creamy moth had a wing span of about 20 mm. The wings had dark flecks - about three rows on the fore wings and two on the hind wings. The trailing margin of each wing had a thin dark broken line and a short white fringe.&#xD;
Attracted to garden lights on a warm night - mixed native trees around.</description>
      <category>id~Idaea philocosma</category>
      <category>tag~moth-cream</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a33b64ced2a896262001a71.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 11:51:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garrha ocellifera</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a31080fed2a8962620011ac.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This small silky peach-coloured moth had a large irregularly shaped black patch in the middle of each fore wing. Small black specks were sen along the trailing margin and the sub-marginal border. Thorax was also a sooty black. Wing span was about 15 mm.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights in suburban garden. Plenty of native trees around.&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Garrha ocellifera</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a31080fed2a8962620011ac.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 11:02:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apricia jovialis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a2e838ded2a896262000819.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This attractive jumping spider was just a little over 5 mm long. The body was black with a banded yellow pattern on the abdomen. Legs were brown and pedipalps were covered with white hairs.&#xD;
Spotted on outer wall -suburban house.</description>
      <category>id~Apricia jovialis</category>
      <category>tag~spider-jumping</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a2e838ded2a896262000819.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 13:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caladenia alpina</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a25322fed2a89e67a0000c5.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These beautiful orchids were about 25 cms tall. Flowers were on stout stems with pink tinges on the hood-forming central sepal. The other sepals and petals were spread out. The labellum had dark reddish spots and transverse bars. Leaves were fleshy and lanceolate (partially visible in photo).&#xD;
Spotted along the track in an alpine national park (Baw Baw NP)</description>
      <category>id~Caladenia alpina</category>
      <category>tag~orchid</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a25322fed2a89e67a0000c5.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 11:36:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxyopes spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a23ec84ed2a89ee910002c0.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This small lynx spider had a leg span of about 10 to 12 mm. Legs were pale, long and spikey. The body had black and white stripes through the length of it and what looked like a fuzz of fine red hairs around the cephalothorax making it look like an attractive two-toned spider at a glance. Palps were large and dark suggesting that it was male.&#xD;
Spotted in a suburban garden.</description>
      <category>id~Oxyopes spp.</category>
      <category>tag~spider</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a23ec84ed2a89ee910002c0.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 12:27:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endosimilis stilbealis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a1f75cded2a89132c000007.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This is one of the most attractive of pyralids. It sat upright resting on its legs, hlding up a recurved abdomen. Wings ( span about 15 mm) were a beautiful and rich mix of deep red and orange. The fore wings were divided into three parts with the mid section showing a dark spot near the costa. Antennae were swept back.&#xD;
Attracted to bright lights in the house.&#xD;
My thanks to Cathy Powers for the ID.</description>
      <category>id~Endosimilis stilbealis</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a1f75cded2a89132c000007.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 03:14:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a1ea635ed2a89928e000192.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This large cossid moth had a wing span of at least 70 mm. There were no patterns on its grey wings however, the wings looked like sand-paper. The hind wings were shorter and a beautiful purplish brown. some of this colour was also seen in the abdominal segments nearer the thorax. Abdomen was very thick. antennae were short, feathery and brown.&#xD;
 It was interesting to see this moth in flight - lifting its heavy body into the air after a short "taxiing". On ground, the moth could be heard fluttering from several metres away. &#xD;
Spotted under bright lights near a national park. Need help to ID this large cossid. thanks.</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a1ea635ed2a89928e000192.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 12:28:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endoxyla secta</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a1ea1b8ed2a8962be004fdf.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This Cossid moth would have had a wingspan of about 60 mm. Short black lines marked both fore wings. Broad white streaks near the costal margins made this moth stand out from the other grey cossids.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights near a national park.</description>
      <category>id~Endoxyla secta</category>
      <category>tag~moth-grey</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a1ea1b8ed2a8962be004fdf.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 12:08:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a1e9d76ed2a8962be004fd7.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A beautiful speckled grey and silver moth about 35mm long. Thorax had a distinct inverted "V" in black. Legs were heavily "furry" and antennae, feathery nearer the base. Hind wings were a pearly brown. Abdomen was quite thick.&#xD;
Again, spotted under bright lights near a national park with mixed natives.</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~moth-grey</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a1e9d76ed2a8962be004fd7.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:48:45 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a1e959bed2a8962be004fbd.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A Cossid moth about 40 mm long. Fore wings were a pale grey with a central darker area. Midway along the costa was a semicircular patch of white. A short diagonal patch of dark grey was seen along the trailing edge of the fore wings. The thorax had the inverted black "V" as in all most other cossids.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights near native trees. &#xD;
One of many cossids spotted that year. According to Peter Marriott , this is near Trismelasmos donovani. My thanks to Peter M for the ID and to Cathy Powers for facilitating the identification.</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~moth-grey</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a1e959bed2a8962be004fbd.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:18:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endoxyla spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a1e921eed2a895718000005.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A fawn-coloured Cossid about 40 mm long, No distinct patterns on wings but darker along the veins. Antennae were brown and feathery. Thorax had a faint dark inverted "V" shape.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights near a national park.&#xD;
I believe this is an Endoxyla moth. My thanks to peter Marriott for confirming the genus.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Endoxyla spp.</category>
      <category>tag~moth-brown</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a1e921eed2a895718000005.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:02:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endoxyla spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a1e8d09ed2a8962be004f76.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This gigantic and heavy moth was about 65 mm long and looked like a roll of burnt paper. The fore wings had attractive blotchy patches of black, brown, grey and white with the inner margins folding over each other in a wave. The grey thorax had two short black tufts of setae. Antennae were smooth and short. The abdomen was covered with dense grey setae; it looked and felt heavy.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights near a national park.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Endoxyla spp.</category>
      <category>tag~moth-female</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a1e8d09ed2a8962be004f76.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 10:41:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endoxyla spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a1e8973ed2a8962be004f68.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This cossid moth was about 45 mm long. Mostly grey with tinges of light brown. The basal part of the fore wings had hatched markings of dark grey, the pattern running down to the apices of each wing. Hind wings were grey with the colour fading towards the sub marginal area. On each side of the thorax, running along the length of it was a broad band of dense white setae and just inside the band was a black line of setae ending posteriorly in a thick tuft. Antennae were feathery.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights near national park.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Endoxyla spp.</category>
      <category>tag~moth-grey-brown</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a1e8973ed2a8962be004f68.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 10:26:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culama anthracica</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a1e83e2ed2a89928e00015e.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This cossid moth was all grey with thin black lines across the wings like tiger-skin stripes, with the pattern changing slightly in the submarginal area. The thorax had dense grey and white setae. Antennae were feathery - male. Wing span about 50 mm.&#xD;
My thanks to Cathy Powers &amp; Peter Marriott for the ID.</description>
      <category>id~Culama anthracica</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a1e83e2ed2a89928e00015e.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 10:06:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stigmatium spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a155688ed2a892229000130.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A black beetle about 25 mm long with  bands of brown, black and white patterns on the elytra and thorax. There were small patches of brown at the apices. . The elytra and thorax were covered with short stiff setae and each elytron had a narrow white  line near the apex. The thorax was narrower posteriorly. The head had a crown-shaped pattern posterior to the eyes.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Stigmatium spp.</category>
      <category>tag~beetle</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a155688ed2a892229000130.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 11:15:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heliomystis electrica</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5a0a590fed2a8962be0009da.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A brown moth with wing span about 40 mm. Thorax was covered with short dense brown setae. Fore wings were sectioned into three by thin dark jagged lines.  The hind wings were a bright orange with dark brown sub marginal area. Antennae were feathery.&#xD;
This moth was high up on the wall so the photo is a little skewed. Also, could not get rid of the pesky alates that were everywhere last night.  My thanks to Cathy Powers for the ID.</description>
      <category>id~Heliomystis electrica</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5a0a590fed2a8962be0009da.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 02:56:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schedotrioza spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F59cddf48ed2a89c0fd00005f.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These were attractive thin-walled urn-shaped galls that appeared to be about 10 to 12 mm tall. The apical openings through which the adults would have emerged had jagged edges which were a deep pink. This colour bled into the pale green bodies and bases of the galls.&#xD;
Spotted on the upper surface of eucalyptus leaves - Gum tree species not known.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Schedotrioza spp.</category>
      <category>tag~leaf-gall</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/59cddf48ed2a89c0fd00005f.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 05:57:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanwellia grisea</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F59be6de4ed2a8957de0007c8.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A long-legged dark brown spider with large fangs spotted crawling around the back yard.  Fine short hairs on the legs and abdomen gave it a silky look. The small abdomen and large palps suggest that it's a male.</description>
      <category>id~Stanwellia grisea</category>
      <category>tag~spider</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/59be6de4ed2a8957de0007c8.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 12:53:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F59bd1c11ed2a8957de0003b7.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A pale moth with a wing span of about 20 mm. Each fore wing had a slightly dark patch outlined by dark flecks. Labial palps were close together, stout and recurved with dense setae at the base. Trailing fore wing margins were fringed.&#xD;
I need help with identifying this moth. Thanks. I have checked Oecophoridae and Gelechioidea but can't find a match ! </description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/59bd1c11ed2a8957de0003b7.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 12:52:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Praxis pandesma</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F59a3c9bbed2a890f2e004ad9.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A dark moth with a wing span of about 35 to 40 mm with dense setae on thorax and legs. Fore wings had scalloped trailing margins. Faint flecks of yellow-green were seen on costa and submarginal areas of wings. Feathery antennae were a deep red. Labial palps short.&#xD;
Could not make out much else against the darkness of the velvety wings but could see fine wavy lines. There were about three of these moths around bright lights on a cool evening.&#xD;
&#xD;
My thanks to Cathy Powers and Peter Marriott for the ID.</description>
      <category>id~Praxis pandesma</category>
      <category>tag~moth-black</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/59a3c9bbed2a890f2e004ad9.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 07:55:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apiomorpha frenchi</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F597e8a6ced2a89c20c000001.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>An almost cylindrical gall with a slightly broader base (point of attachment to the stem). The gall appeared woody with a rough exterior. A drier gall seen on the same tree appeared to have annular splits. &#xD;
The apical end of the gall had rounded edges with a depressed centre and perfectly circular hole.&#xD;
Spotted on ?  Eucalyptus blakelyi (Blakely's red gum) in the Weddin Mountains National Park, NSW.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Apiomorpha frenchi</category>
      <category>tag~eucalypt-galls</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/597e8a6ced2a89c20c000001.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 01:54:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creiis corniculatus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F597e872eed2a89aae50026fe.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These were small slightly flattened trumpet-shaped lerps spotted on eucalyptus leaves. The broader part of these lerps were transparent and appeared fragile. Each of these lerps appeared to have a nymph inside with their pale orange bodies clearly visible through the transparent lerp shell.&#xD;
Unlike lerps of Glycaspis species, I could not see any ants crawling around these lerps. I assume therefore that these lerps are not made of the same material as the Glycaspis species. Also, this species of Creiis lerps seemed keratinous. Various birds feed on lerps but a study on lerp-feeding by birds suggests that birds avoided the Creiis species of lerps.&#xD;
Spotted on Mugga Ironbark (Eucalyptus sideroxylon) in the Cocoparra National Park, New South Wales&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Creiis corniculatus</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/597e872eed2a89aae50026fe.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 01:35:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bondia nigella</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F594e55cfed2a89ff64000032.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small silky black moth about 6 mm long with tufts of scales on the fore wings. On each fore wing was a small gold crescent, about one-third of the distance from the trailing margin. Labial palps were recurved and covered with setae. Some banding in the legs visible.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights after a warm day near a national park (Dandenong Ranges)&#xD;
My thanks to Cathy Powers who has identified this beauty as Bondia nigella. Family: Carposinidae&#xD;
( Please add Bondia nigella. Thank you.)&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Bondia nigella</category>
      <category>tag~moth-black</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/594e55cfed2a89ff64000032.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 12:14:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cymatoderma elegans</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F59429a3ded2a890cca0014f7.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A large brown paper-thin fruiting body with a ruffled upper surface and beautiful white pore surface (underside) arising from a damp log. The fruiting body had a very short stipe.&#xD;
Spotted in a  temperate rain forest.&#xD;
My thanks to John Walter for the ID and information highlighting differences between Podoscypha and Cymatoderma.&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Cymatoderma elegans</category>
      <category>tag~fungus</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/59429a3ded2a890cca0014f7.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 14:36:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxycanus antipoda</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5938f689ed2a8994430002ad.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A handsome ghost moth with dark tented wings . The wings had a span of about 40 mm and showed pale curvy patterns. Antennae were feathery and the thorax had dense brown setae.&#xD;
Spotted near a national park - mixed native trees. &#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Oxycanus antipoda</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5938f689ed2a8994430002ad.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 07:06:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phaeographis mucronata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F59258b08ed2a893e6b00268a.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Small pale greyish-white plaques (photobiont) were seen on moist thick bark of a eucalypt. Each of these plaques had a scribbly lead-grey pattern. These long, branched reproductive parts (Lirellae) are the apothecia.&#xD;
Spotted on coastal banksia - Snowy River Estuary.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Phaeographis mucronata</category>
      <category>tag~lichen</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/59258b08ed2a893e6b00268a.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 13:37:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ramboldia laeta</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F592589c7ed2a893e6b002683.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Greyish white plaques with small brilliant red irregular convex discs which produce spores (apothecia). The apothecia were scattered on the grey crust.&#xD;
Spotted on a damp tree trunk - coastal /estuarine at the high tide mark. </description>
      <category>id~Ramboldia laeta</category>
      <category>tag~lichen</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/592589c7ed2a893e6b002683.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 13:28:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collema spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F592587d5ed2a893e6b00267d.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Small patches of green slimy lichen with flat bluish-white apothecia on damp tree trunks. Spotted on coastal Banksia at high tide mark.</description>
      <category>id~Collema spp.</category>
      <category>tag~lichen</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/592587d5ed2a893e6b00267d.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 13:23:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hericium coralloides</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F592584afed2a893e6b002672.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This beautiful toothed coral fungus was seen in two clumps, a large one about 170 mm across and a smaller one within the tree hollow. The small clump was fresh, white and highly branched with multiple soft spines. The larger clump was slightly old, drier with stiffer spines.&#xD;
Spotted on a damp tree stump - Beech&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Hericium coralloides</category>
      <category>tag~fungus</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/592584afed2a893e6b002672.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 13:12:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anestia ombrophanes</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F58ec5e19ed2a894865001ae7.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Three clouded footman males were seen fluttering around for awhile before settling on a door frame. On closer inspection I could see one of them was successful in finding and mating with a wingless female seen here as a furry white ovoid shape with thin black bands and pale orange spots along the sides. The males were of two sizes and had distinctly pectinated antennae. The mating male can be seen head pointing downwards. Beside the female was a hairy cocoon and an empty pupal case probably recently vacated by the female. Within the hairy cage was also small wrinkled piece of skin shed by the caterpillar before pupating. Pic 3 was taken 6 days later when two of the moths had flown away and the other was clear-off the female. The female had started laying eggs seen here as minute glistening orbs. The female had the same colours as seen on the caterpillar. Will wait to see what happens next.....</description>
      <category>id~Anestia ombrophanes</category>
      <category>tag~moths</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/58ec5e19ed2a894865001ae7.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 04:44:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Papilio anactus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F58d26b06ed2a896341000bc6.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This Chrysalis was seen about 12 days after the small early instar of this butterfly was seen. It was hard to differentiate between the pupa and plant stem as it looked very much in colour &amp; form like a stem gall induced by a citrus gall wasp. One end of the 3 cm pupa was bifurcated.</description>
      <category>id~Papilio anactus</category>
      <category>tag~chrysalis</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/58d26b06ed2a896341000bc6.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 12:21:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Papilio anactus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F58d269eced2a896341000bbe.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Dainty Swallowtail Butterfly caterpillar - early instar</description>
      <category>id~Papilio anactus</category>
      <category>tag~caterpillar</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/58d269eced2a896341000bbe.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 12:14:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nacoleia rhoeoalis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F58ca74d0ed2a8960a2000e48.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This moth had a wing span of about 20 mm. Wings were greyish green with thin black wriggly lines and dark brown patches. each fore wing showed a small patch of white.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights near a suburban garden.&#xD;
My thanks to Cathy Powers for the ID.</description>
      <category>id~Nacoleia rhoeoalis</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/58ca74d0ed2a8960a2000e48.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 11:23:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pterohelaeus spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F58c9e7b9ed2a89482600008b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This dusty blue beetle was about 13 mm long. The dorso-ventrally flattened body had a flange around both the thorax and elytra.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights in a suburban garden on a very warm night.&#xD;
This could be P.peltatus but needs confirmation.</description>
      <category>id~Pterohelaeus spp.</category>
      <category>tag~beetle-flat</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/58c9e7b9ed2a89482600008b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 01:22:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F58c3dea5ed2a896b0300000e.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small butterfly with fawn coloured wings with iridescent blue tones near the wing bases. The wings which looked fragile could have had a span of about 15 mm.&#xD;
Spotted flying close to the ground over open grass land. Also present were other blues like Zizina labradus.&#xD;
&#xD;
( I believe this is Zizula hylax. Could someone confirm please. Thanks)</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~butterfly-small</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/58c3dea5ed2a896b0300000e.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 11:34:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syringoseca rhodoxantha</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F58ba1c3aed2a89389000241b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small attractive red-orange moth with fine cream patterns. Wing span about 20 mm. Re-curved labial palps and long thin antennae.</description>
      <category>id~Syringoseca rhodoxantha</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/58ba1c3aed2a89389000241b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 01:50:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endoxyla spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5895cd71ed2a89979d000001.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This attractive Cossid moth would have been about 40 to 45 mm long. Has the distinct black upside down "V" pattern on the thorax seen in Endoxyla genus.&#xD;
Spotted unfurling its wings. I would greatly appreciate any assistance with an ID. Thanks.</description>
      <category>id~Endoxyla spp.</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5895cd71ed2a89979d000001.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 12:51:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caulerpa cactoides</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5889daf4ed2a89d10f000bb3.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This green seaweed (Caulerpa cactoides) appeared in two forms, one as a cluster and the other as an elongated string of vesicles attached to flattened median segments. This variation in appearance is apparently due to wave action in different parts of the bay. &#xD;
Pic 2 shows some brown (root-like) rhizoids at the base of the seaweed.&#xD;
Spotted washed ashore at Westernport Bay -at low tide. Native to Australia.&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Caulerpa cactoides</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5889daf4ed2a89d10f000bb3.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 11:25:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maratus volans</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F5870478fed2a89f464000cc6.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This cute little jumping spider was about 5 mm long. The black cephalothorax had white and orange stripes in the anterior part and just white stripes in the posterior section. The abdomen had beautiful orange blue and green colours with iridescence. legs were covered with setae and the palps were fluffy with white setae.&#xD;
Spotted near a creek in dappled shade (Cardinia Reservoir Park)</description>
      <category>id~Maratus volans</category>
      <category>tag~spider</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/5870478fed2a89f464000cc6.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 01:48:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chaetophyes compacta</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F584f622fed2a89fb9d000001.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small female tube spittlebug resting on the tube created perhaps by its nymphs. The tube looked like a concrete horn with dried-up spittle along the tree branch at the opening of the tube. The female spittlebug has a green head and thorax with dark tinted wings.&#xD;
Spotted on a young eucalyptus tree in a botanical garden ( Cranbourne Gardens)&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Chaetophyes compacta</category>
      <category>tag~adult-female</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/584f622fed2a89fb9d000001.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 02:56:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crucibulum laeve</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F57b1bff7ed2a89450f000462.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>-</description>
      <category>id~Crucibulum laeve</category>
      <category>tag~fungus</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/57b1bff7ed2a89450f000462.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 13:17:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cordyceps gunnii</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F574e4990ed2a89e668000ed9.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Poking out of the ground to about 90 mm were a number of these black club-shaped fruiting bodies. Structurally they were differentiated into black clubs above and pale greenish yellow stems below. The older thicker clubs had white fluffy material on the dark clubs.&#xD;
Spotted under a mature Acacia tree. There were about 20 and all well separated.&#xD;
The white material on the fruiting bodies are thread-like spores. They break up into 3 -5 mm long part spores which penetrate the ground and infect caterpillars of moths which could be well below the surface, even up to 40 cms. The fungus consumes the soft tissue of the host and grows up wards to the ground surface were black fruiting bodies appear and thicken to maturity. Moth larvae of the genus Oxycanus ( Hepialidae) are said to be the common hosts to this fungus. &#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Cordyceps gunnii</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/574e4990ed2a89e668000ed9.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 02:44:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calosoma (Australodrepa) schayeri</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F56fd0ac0ed2a89615500006e.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This 20 mm long beetle looked very different to other ground beetles because of its flattened body and a thorax that is notched both anteriorly and posteriorly. Elytra showed fine parallel ridges and had a metallic sheen which reflected purple and teal colours. Legs were long had short spines.&#xD;
&#xD;
These ground beetles are said to feed on caterpillars. They are strongly attracted to U-V emitting lights and can congregate in large numbers but do not stay in one place for long. They stay hidden during the day but are very active at night. &#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Calosoma (Australodrepa) schayeri</category>
      <category>tag~beetle</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/56fd0ac0ed2a89615500006e.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 11:40:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mictis profana</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F56e77573ed2a89d33600001b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Pic 1 shows the 5th instar and Pic 2, the 3rd instar of the Crusader Bug. The younger nymph had yellow bands on his legs and a small yellow band on the antennal tips. The 5th instar shows a better developed pronotum and smart bolero-like yellow wing buds. The antennal tip were completely yellow and legs completely brown by this stage. Both were seen on the same young wattle plant.</description>
      <category>id~Mictis profana</category>
      <category>tag~bug</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/56e77573ed2a89d33600001b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 02:44:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lachnodius spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F56b6e782ed2a89d4ab000327.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This female adult felt scale looked like a 5 mm long and wide, slightly raised peach-coloured patch on a leaf. The leaf surface surrounding it was damaged. faint body segments could be seen on the upper surface which had wispy white waxy secretions. The underside (pic 1) showed three pairs of legs, a slight depression between the first pair of legs ( ? mouth) and well defined abdominal segments. A pair of antennae were visible when the scale was turned over.&#xD;
Spotted on a eucalyptus tree in a reserve. Several leaves were affected by these scale but there was no more than one per leaf.&#xD;
My thanks to Dr Lyn Cook who identified this as Lobimago sp. , a Lobe-margin Felt Scale. Family: Eriococcidae&#xD;
Dr Cook writes " Was in genus Lachnodius but transferred to Lobimago by Hardy et al in 2011." . At present on ALA as Lachnodius.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Lachnodius spp.</category>
      <category>tag~adult-female</category>
      <category>tag~scale-insect</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/56b6e782ed2a89d4ab000327.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 07:00:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pterohelaeus spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F56b0397eed2a89d94d00003f.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>About 12 mm long this black beetle had broadly convex body with ridged elytra and a thin marginal flange. The pronotum showed broader flanges and thick lateral margins. Head and eyes were small. Antennae had beaded segments.&#xD;
Spotted on grass in a park.</description>
      <category>id~Pterohelaeus spp.</category>
      <category>tag~beetle</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/56b0397eed2a89d94d00003f.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 05:12:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schedotrioza spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F569c318ced2a89f5e100002e.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These small dry star-bursts of psyllid galls looked like rusted metal flowers stuck to the upper surfaces of gum leaves. These eruptions looked a lot "neater" than some of the galls induced by these little hemipterans.&#xD;
Spotted on what looked like Silver-leaf Stringy Bark ( E.cinerea) in a reserve.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Schedotrioza spp.</category>
      <category>tag~galls</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/569c318ced2a89f5e100002e.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:39:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Villa spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F569c2e05ed2a89f5e100001f.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These attractive beeflies were seen mating amongst leaf litter. There is clear distinction between the female and the male with the female having well separated eyes(Pic 3) and the male with large eyes together with only a thin line of separation (Pic 2). The male beefly has a single bright white spot at the base of each wing as seen in pic 2. The female has no such spots and (which is on the left-hand side) has brighter white abdominal bands and a pair of lateral tufts of white setae.&#xD;
Spotted in a nature reserve.</description>
      <category>id~Villa spp.</category>
      <category>tag~adult-female</category>
      <category>tag~bee-fly</category>
      <category>tag~male-adult</category>
      <category>tag~mating</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/569c2e05ed2a89f5e100001f.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:20:47 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptophasa rubescens</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F568d0d60ed2a895c190000bb.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>About 20 mm long this moth had pale yellow wings with hints of copper. Wings were tented, giving the body a wedge shape. The head and anterior thorax were almost white and the paleness continued along the costa. Thoracic setae had dark tips. Feathery antennae stretched out and were almost two-thirds the body length.</description>
      <category>id~Cryptophasa rubescens</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/568d0d60ed2a895c190000bb.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 12:56:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turneromyia spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F568d0b35ed2a895c190000a8.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A 20 mm black wasp with striking thin white markings on thorax and abdomen. Head and legs showed diffuse white patches. Legs showed short spikes and appeared unusually long and were held spread out around the body like a spider.&#xD;
Spotted making a burrow in soil beside a walking track.</description>
      <category>id~Turneromyia spp.</category>
      <category>tag~wasp</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/568d0b35ed2a895c190000a8.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 12:44:50 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sandalodes superbus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F566c15f0ed2a89b5f50003ac.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Described as the largest and most robust of its species, this very dark male jumping spider was about 13 mm long. Fangs were large and above dark eyes was a furry brow. Palps were dark and long. Front legs were long and had faint white banding like the other legs. The abdomen had a thin white line along the anterior margin and a flattened "x" pattern in white. two pairs of white specks were seen in front of and posterior to the X mark.&#xD;
Spotted trying to catch a small fly in a local garden. </description>
      <category>id~Sandalodes superbus</category>
      <category>tag~spider</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/566c15f0ed2a89b5f50003ac.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 12:48:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nisista serrata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5663b745ed2a89b5f50001d4.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A beautiful brown moth with thin zig- zag lines on the fore wings and a wing span of 40mm. the trailing wing margins appear serrated.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights near a national park ( Dandenong Ranges).&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Nisista serrata</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5663b745ed2a89b5f50001d4.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 04:22:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aleucosia calophthalma</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F56618cd0ed2a89b5f500010f.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A medium-sized bee-fly with slender narrow wings that were mostly clear. The leading edges of the wings were dark with the inner margins being thrown into waves. The abdomen was longer than in most other bee-flies.</description>
      <category>id~Aleucosia calophthalma</category>
      <category>tag~bee-fly</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/56618cd0ed2a89b5f500010f.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 12:57:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deinopis subrufa</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F566173f7ed2a89b5f5000101.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A net-casting spider with its blue rectangular net which was loosely slung from the front legs. The spider was prepared to get its meal at this stage. &#xD;
Pics 2 &amp; 3 are of the spider at day time - it was magical to see the blue net which she would have made in the evening for some supper that night. Hoping I'd be able to get an action shot next time and a shot of those enormous eyes ! &#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Deinopis subrufa</category>
      <category>tag~behaviour</category>
      <category>tag~spider</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/566173f7ed2a89b5f5000101.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 11:21:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oreisplanus perornata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F56528599ed2a89e56e000d77.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This dark attractive skipper had a wing span of 30 mm. The upper side of the fore wings had small rectangular patches of cream. The trailing margins also showed a narrow margin of broken cream patches. The upper side of each hind wing ( just visible) had a bright orange patch. As with most skippers, the thorax was covered with dense olive green setae. White spots were seen on a dark head.</description>
      <category>id~Oreisplanus perornata</category>
      <category>tag~butterfly</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/56528599ed2a89e56e000d77.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 03:22:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nyssus coloripes</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F564dbe05ed2a89e56e000c44.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A fast moving attractive Swift Spider with black cephalothorax and abdomen, black and white banded hind legs and orange front legs. The body had white patterns along the sides, a median white line on the cephalothorax and broken white pattern along the midline of the abdomen.&#xD;
Its behaviour and erratic movements are a mimicry of the pompilid wasp - the orange legs move up and down like the orange antennae of the wasps. &#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Nyssus coloripes</category>
      <category>tag~spider</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/564dbe05ed2a89e56e000c44.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 12:27:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stenolemus bituberus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F564b247aed2a89e56e000b79.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A delicate-looking predacious bug from the Reduviidae family. The long legs were covered with fuzzy setae. The mid and hind legs were resting on the web silk while the front pair of legs were held up folded in front of the head. The antennae looked much like another pair of legs.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Stenolemus bituberus</category>
      <category>tag~bug</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/564b247aed2a89e56e000b79.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 13:13:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Labium spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5649292aed2a89e56e000a5c.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This wasp was about 20 mm long with yellow markings on thorax and head. Scutellum was yellow as were parts of the legs. The abdomen was an amber colour and slightly dorso-ventrally flattened. Wings were clear.&#xD;
My thanks to Tony D for identifying the genus and for the following information "Beautiful wasp! Features of note for Labium are the large hind claws, ovipositor just barely projecting in females (as seen here), antennae more or less semi-clavate, and head longish below eyes (shown in third pic)." </description>
      <category>id~Labium spp.</category>
      <category>tag~wasp</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5649292aed2a89e56e000a5c.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:58:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scarabaeidae spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5645d22bed2a89e56e000939.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This beetle was about 22 mm long, robust with dark head and thorax and purplish brown elytra. Antennal ends were lamellate. &#xD;
Dense golden setae on the underside.</description>
      <category>id~Scarabaeidae spp.</category>
      <category>tag~beetle</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5645d22bed2a89e56e000939.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 12:14:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carabidae spp., Sarothrocrepis civica</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F56402c08ed2a89e56e0006e7.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small black beetle about 5 mm long with glossy black elytra with pale patches at the base. The elytra appeared to stop short of the last few abdominal segments. The scape of antennae were a pale brown and appeared to have a short spine.&#xD;
Subfamily: Lebiinae&#xD;
Thanks to Chris Lindorff for helping with identifying the beetle.</description>
      <category>id~Carabidae spp.</category>
      <category>id~Sarothrocrepis civica</category>
      <category>tag~beetle</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/56402c08ed2a89e56e0006e7.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 05:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thema psammoxantha</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F564028a9ed2a89e56e0006e2.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small ( about 10 mm long) but attractive moth with pale yellow wings and a broad dark brown marking covering part of the thorax and extending down the inner margins of the fore wings. This moth also had a short brown streak extending down from the tornus suggesting that it was male. &#xD;
Antennae were thin and swept back. labial palps were brushy, yellow and bare recurved tips.&#xD;
Spotted resting on a leaf of an Agapanthus plant - local garden.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Thema psammoxantha</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/564028a9ed2a89e56e0006e2.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 05:08:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omorgus spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5636025fed2a89e56e00031d.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A heavily sclerotised Hide Beetle with ridged and sculptured elytra and thorax. It was a dusty brown and about 12 mm in length. The head was deflexed and it was difficult to see any details except briefly. Short segmented antennae ended in a three segmented club.</description>
      <category>id~Omorgus spp.</category>
      <category>tag~beetle</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5636025fed2a89e56e00031d.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 12:19:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nataxa flavescens</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5635f44fed2a89e56e0002e5.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This sooty moth had a wing span of about 40 mm. The upper side of the fore wings had large white patches. The undersides of wings were plain and similar in colour to the upper surfaces. The head and thorax had tufts of bright yellow setae. The banded abdomen had dense sooty, white and yellow setae giving it a furry appearance. &#xD;
Antennae were slightly feathery.</description>
      <category>id~Nataxa flavescens</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5635f44fed2a89e56e0002e5.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 11:19:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trioza spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F562460a6ed2a89401600acaa.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This eucalyptus tree with slightly pendulous branches and small clusters of creamy white flowers had delicate young leaves with their tips curled into thick cups. These cups appeared to have a membranous pale or brown lid (pic 5). Some of these cups had ants clustering around them as in pic 4. On opening one of these lidded "cups', I found a 3 mm psyllid nymph with small red wide-set eyes, orange thorax and green abdomen. Wings buds were dark with a white substance stuck to them. The tree had several young leaves with these galls.&#xD;
Spotted on a box gum ( ? Eucalyptus microcarpa) in a bushland reserve.&#xD;
I am not sure of the relationship between the ants and this species of psyllid. The gall-forming behaviour seems similar to Trioza species of psyllid. &#xD;
My thanks to Ken Walker for confirming that this is Trioza ( species not known).&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Trioza spp.</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/562460a6ed2a89401600acaa.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 03:16:54 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyalarcta huebneri</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5620d0eced2a89401600ab2e.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This larva, with a mottled head and thoracic segments was encased in a silken bag (about 18 mm long) covered with small pieces of bark, leaves and sticks. &#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Hyalarcta huebneri</category>
      <category>tag~moth-larva</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5620d0eced2a89401600ab2e.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 10:26:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Therevidae spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F56151682ed2a89401600a5b2.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A vermiform larva about 20 mm long with pointy ends. The tail end appeared bifid. The white body had deep blue patterns.&#xD;
Spotted on dry soil in a garden. Did not appear to like sun light and actively dug through the dry dirt.</description>
      <category>id~Therevidae spp.</category>
      <category>tag~fly</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/56151682ed2a89401600a5b2.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 12:56:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puccinia oxalidis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5608c686ed2a89b06c00141f.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Seen on Oxalis corymbosa.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Puccinia oxalidis</category>
      <category>tag~fungus</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5608c686ed2a89b06c00141f.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 04:48:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pterostylis pedunculata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5608afabed2a89b06c00140b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Could not get a shot of leaves or whole plant. Spotted by a walking track - </description>
      <category>id~Pterostylis pedunculata</category>
      <category>tag~orchid</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5608afabed2a89b06c00140b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 03:10:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiloglottis jeanesii</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5607e8e7ed2a89b06c0013d8.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>The flowers in this species were smaller and not as robust as in C. valida which has purplish flowers. The flowers had just a slight tinge of purple and the leaves, that were paired were all green and small. Flower buds (pic 3) were a pale green.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Chiloglottis jeanesii</category>
      <category>tag~orchid</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5607e8e7ed2a89b06c0013d8.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 13:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amaurodon viridis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55d17101ed2a89db81001170.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Small velvety patches and veins of crust fungus in beautiful shades of blue in a tree hollow. The surface was covered with beads of moisture. &#xD;
Spotted on a large eucalypt.</description>
      <category>id~Amaurodon viridis</category>
      <category>tag~fungi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55d17101ed2a89db81001170.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 05:28:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pterostylis grandiflora</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55c2cca3ed2a89db81000a9f.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A small plant about 10 cm high with lance-shaped leaves. The flowers were attractive with the central sepal (green) and lateral petals (brown) fused to form a hood, rising up and over the labellum. The lateral sepals were fused at the base and rose up on either side to erect points. The inside of the hood showed broad white stripes (pic 5). The same colouring could be seen on the outer side of the flower (pic 3).</description>
      <category>id~Pterostylis grandiflora</category>
      <category>tag~orchid</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55c2cca3ed2a89db81000a9f.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 02:55:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poronia erici</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55b4ca43ed2a89db810001b9.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Small ( 6mm wide) flat pale discs with tapering bases seen on herbivore dung pellet ( possibly Kangaroo) The pale surfaces had minute evenly spaced holes (ostioles) - some of them showed puckering around the edges. The discs had irregular margins.&#xD;
Spotted in a national park which is a free range for kangaroos, wallabies, wombats and rabbits. ( Churchill National Park)&#xD;
( This is Poronia erici but there is no listing on ALA. Ref : Fuhrer 2005. Could this be added, please Thanks)</description>
      <category>id~Poronia erici</category>
      <category>tag~fungi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55b4ca43ed2a89db810001b9.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 11:53:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geoglossum spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55b4c605ed2a89db810001ac.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Hardly visible on a bed of moss were these thin sculptured stalks with smooth club-shaped tips. The whole fruiting body was about 30 mm tall including the 15 mm club-shaped fertile tips.&#xD;
Spotted on moss beds along walking track - Churchill National Park . There were several of these in a moist patch of moss. </description>
      <category>id~Geoglossum spp.</category>
      <category>tag~fungi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55b4c605ed2a89db810001ac.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 11:35:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amauroderma rude</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55ae2feaed2a89158b0008f4.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>The fruiting bodies of this very tough woody fungus looked like large rusty nails arising from the ground. The flattened caps ( upto 50 mm across) had concentric rings and were slightly puckered. The underside showed dark reddish brown pores - no white "bloom" as the cap were old. The stems were firm and slightly velvety in dry specimens. Some of the caps had incorporated grass blades ( pic 3).&#xD;
Spotted on a damp forest floor - mixed natives but mostly young mountain ash ( Eucalyptus regnens) </description>
      <category>id~Amauroderma rude</category>
      <category>tag~fungi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55ae2feaed2a89158b0008f4.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 11:41:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galerina patagonica</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55ab0893ed2a89158b000683.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Attractive clump of toffee coloured caps with slight convexity, a small discrete umbo and rolled in margins. Gills were a pale brown. these must have been covered by a thin cortina which could be seen tearing-off some of the younger caps (pic 3). The remnants of a brown spore-stained cortina could be seen as a wispy annulus around the stipe. The stipe below the annulus was a dark brown with white fibrils.&#xD;
Spotted groiwng as a clump on dead wood in a forest with mixed native trees.</description>
      <category>id~Galerina patagonica</category>
      <category>tag~fungi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55ab0893ed2a89158b000683.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 02:16:51 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astraeus hygrometricus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55a8ddf2ed2a89158b0005d1.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These were large earthstars, about 45 mm across. They were fully open with split pale rays of areolated outer skins (exoperidia). In the centre was a smooth rounded spore sac with a central pore through which the spores are released. These earthstars were sessile .&#xD;
Spotted on moist ground under pine trees.</description>
      <category>id~Astraeus hygrometricus</category>
      <category>tag~fungi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55a8ddf2ed2a89158b0005d1.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 10:50:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydnum repandum</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55a1d22bed2a89158b000312.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>With contorted pale orange caps about 25 mm, these fruiting bodies were growing close to the ground. The cap margins were mealy and white.The fertile under-surface had densely packed spines or teeth instead of pores and these were slightly decurrent (pic 2). The whote stipe were otherwise smooth.&#xD;
Spotted on sodden forest floor in a reserve.</description>
      <category>id~Hydnum repandum</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55a1d22bed2a89158b000312.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 02:34:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cladonia spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55a1b15eed2a89158b0002d4.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A pale green-grey lichen with lobed leaf-like thalli and upright outgrowths (podetia). Some of the podetia had wide grey cups.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Cladonia spp.</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55a1b15eed2a89158b0002d4.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:14:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laetiporus portentosus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F559d1989ed2a89158b000180.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A clump of contorted brackets forming a 360 mm wide mass that emerged from the trunk of a large living gum tree. The upper surface of the fruiting body was velvety and tan colour. The pale underside had minute pores (pic 3) which had a creamy covering. Some brackets showed a peeling layer (pic 4) which exposed the pore surface.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Laetiporus portentosus</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/559d1989ed2a89158b000180.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 12:37:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russula kalimna</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F557165f4ed2a8918dd00056a.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Caps were a bluish yellow with fine cracks with young ones rising out of the ground like pale purplish puff balls. Mature caps were about 55 mm wide with a central depression. Gills and stipe were cream coloured. The stocky fruiting body was quite close to the ground. The spore print was a pale cream (photo not good enough to post).&#xD;
Spotted in damp soil a eucalyptus forest.</description>
      <category>id~Russula kalimna</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/557165f4ed2a8918dd00056a.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 09:03:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eolophus roseicapillus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F554deb47ed2a899dad000083.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This large gum tree had a beautiful trunk and several hollows. A galah flew to one of the hollows ( pics 1 &amp;2), entered it and came out again after a few minutes and had a good look around. It then flew to perch on a nearby branch (pic 4). Soon after a second bird came out for a few minutes and the two sat outside for awhile (pic 6) before flying away together.&#xD;
Spotted in a reserve near a creek.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Eolophus roseicapillus</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/554deb47ed2a899dad000083.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 11:11:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scioglyptis lyciaria</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5525f27ced2a8957ad0000a6.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>An attractive grey-brown geometrid moth with fine brown and black lines and a wing span of about 50 mm. The wings had narrow black bands contrasting with flashes of white. The undersides of the wings were pale with a black mark on each wing. The dark submarginal areas on each wing was broken by a pale patch.&#xD;
Spotted in a suburban garden.</description>
      <category>id~Scioglyptis lyciaria</category>
      <category>tag~female</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5525f27ced2a8957ad0000a6.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 03:31:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteronympha banksii banksii</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5525eabbed2a8957ad00009b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This attractive dark brown butterfly had a wing span of about 50 mm. Both fore and hind wings had bright yellow patterns much like the common brown, except only the hind wing had a distinct eye spot (on the upper side). This butterfly showed a long style-like yellow marking on the fore wing ( pic 1), which is a sex-brand and seen only in males. The underside of the fore wings showed a dark patch on a background of pale gold with a small eye spot at the apex. The hind wing had beautiful patches of purple with two small eye spots, one near the costal margin and the other near the trailing margin.&#xD;
Spotted on a grass verge in a nature reserve. It was flitting about landing one one clump of grass for a few seconds before going to another.</description>
      <category>id~Heteronympha banksii banksii</category>
      <category>tag~male</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5525eabbed2a8957ad00009b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 02:58:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanyscelis maculata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F551d27d0ed2a89daf20000c8.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These are scale insect galls seen on the adaxial side of the leaf . The broad-based conical outgrowths are female galls. There were two of these, one at the base of the leaf base and another along the main vein. the gall was purplish and had a ring near the base. One of the galls showed two openings and the other a single smooth circular orifice. Also on the leaf surface were many upright tubular structures with apical openings with crenulated margins. These were male galls and they were tinged red.&#xD;
Spotted on a eucalyptus tree - ? species. Nature reserve.&#xD;
My thanks to Dr L.Cook for confirming genus and identifying the species.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Tanyscelis maculata</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <category>tag~scale-insect</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/551d27d0ed2a89daf20000c8.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 11:28:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyposoter spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5518a17eed2a899004000164.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Looking like a 5 mm piece of bird-dropping, this little black and white capsule is a cocoon of an ichneumon wasp. It was attached to the leaves on this young tree and wrapped around it was the skin of its larval host - a lepidopteran. Mimicking bird-dropping and wrapping the skin of the larval host over and around is, apparently, one of the many strategies employed by ichneumonids to escape attacks from hyperparasitoids. Spotted on a young black wattle (Acacia mearnsii) in a nature reserve.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Hyposoter spp.</category>
      <category>tag~cocoon</category>
      <category>tag~parasitoid</category>
      <category>tag~wasp</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5518a17eed2a899004000164.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 01:06:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jalmenus evagoras evagoras</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F5510c507ed2a8974d3000a12.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This observation features just one tree which accommodated every stage of the life-cycle of the common imperial blue or imperial hairstreak butterfly. Pic 1 shows a male butterfly resting beside a pupa. Pic 2 shows a cluster of pale blue-grey eggs with fascinating spikey outer coverings (see reference link in notes). The caterpillar in pic 3 had small horn-like tubercles along the dorsal aspect of the body. Pic 4 shows a cluster of glossy dark pupae and pic 5 shows the exuviae. &#xD;
Pic 6 is that of an adult. &#xD;
Every stage of this butterfly was attended by hoards of ants (Iridomyrmex ). They were running around all over the tree , clustering in large numbers around the pupae. There were ants around the eggs and caterpillar. &#xD;
Another interesting feature was the fine webbing around the eggs and the pupae.&#xD;
Spotted on a black wattle tree (Acacia mearnsii) near wetlands at a retarding basin.</description>
      <category>id~Jalmenus evagoras evagoras</category>
      <category>tag~butterfly</category>
      <category>tag~life-cycle</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/5510c507ed2a8974d3000a12.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 01:59:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poranthera microphylla s.s.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F550aba87ed2a8974d300078f.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Herbaceous plant about 5 cm tall with erect stems bearing clusters of small white flowers. Leaves were elongated egg-shaped, some small and some large. The plant had bright green loculated fruit.</description>
      <category>id~Poranthera microphylla s.s.</category>
      <category>tag~plant-small</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/550aba87ed2a8974d300078f.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 12:01:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sericopimpla australis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F550ab56ced2a8994a9000573.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This small wasp ( a case-moth larvae parasite wasp) was about 10 mm long and very active. The narrow abdomen had thin white bands and a moderate size ovipositor. Head, antennae and thorax were black. The hind legs had black and white markings while the other legs were a pale yellow.&#xD;
Spotted actively searching low plants (in this case the bumblebee weed) in a riparian area.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Sericopimpla australis</category>
      <category>tag~wasp</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/550ab56ced2a8994a9000573.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 11:39:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linum trigynum</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F550ab1c4ed2a8994a9000570.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>An erect plant about a foot high with thin dichotomous branches. The flowers were very small, about 5 mm wide with bright yellow petals. Leaves were small, lanceolate and some had indented margins.&#xD;
Spotted growing amongst other vegetation like dandelion, sorrel and grass by a walking track, in a national park. It was difficult to see this plant separate to the others growing in the area but the bright yellow flowers looked like little stars suspended amongst tall grass. </description>
      <category>id~Linum trigynum</category>
      <category>tag~plant</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/550ab1c4ed2a8994a9000570.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 11:23:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthrax dolabratus</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F550aad41ed2a8994a900056b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This beefly had a wingspan of about 15 mm. The basal part of the wings were black and this ended in a smooth wavy line. The rest of the wings were clear. Head, thorax and abdomen were black. The abdomen had a soft velvety look and was truncated with the rear end covered with pale setae.&#xD;
Spotted in a suburban garden.</description>
      <category>id~Anthrax dolabratus</category>
      <category>tag~bee-fly</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/550aad41ed2a8994a900056b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 11:04:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maratus pavonis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F55023ba8ed2a8974d3000318.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This very attractive jumping spider was only about 6 mm long. It looked like two blobs of yellowish-orange but a closer look revealed a spider with a black cepahalothorax with an ochre colored anterior part and three thin white lines, one in the middle and two laterally placed. The abdomen had two bright orange "c"-shaped patterns facing each other with a central orange patch. All this on a background of very pale teal. The third pair of legs seemed to have dense white setae on the tarsi. The four eyes in the front were a deep green. The palps were white.&#xD;
Spotted on black wattle in a reservoir park.</description>
      <category>id~Maratus pavonis</category>
      <category>tag~male-adult</category>
      <category>tag~spider</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/55023ba8ed2a8974d3000318.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 01:21:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Servaea incana</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54fd8e73ed2a8994a9000014.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A very hairy but attractive jumping spider about 100 mm long. The dorsal aspect of the abdomen had reddish brown pattern with an inverted "Y" in black. Legs were hairy and banded.&#xD;
Spotted on a eucalyptus tree trunk in a park.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Servaea incana</category>
      <category>tag~spider</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54fd8e73ed2a8994a9000014.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 12:13:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hypolaena fastigiata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54fb9ed7ed2a89039300006a.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>The female of a "Tassel Rope-rush" plant. Wiry tough clumps of blue green stems that were mostly prostrate with some branches standing erect up to about 50 cm. no leaves were seen but the branches had nodes with brownish bracts. Terminal flower heads seemed to have what looked like layered bracts with narrow brown flowers.&#xD;
Male plants nearby.</description>
      <category>id~Hypolaena fastigiata</category>
      <category>tag~female-flower</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54fb9ed7ed2a89039300006a.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:59:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hypolaena fastigiata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54fb9b20ed2a890393000062.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Commonly called "Tassel Rope-rush", this plant was growing in a clump and would have been about a foot tall stretched out. The clumps formed mats of wiry branclets that were thick and striated (pic 2). At the nodes were what looked like brown leafy bracts. The attractive branched inflorescence looked like clumps of bracts that were coppery, plump and ovoid. &#xD;
There were no sign of "normal" leaves. Several plants growing together gave the appearance of a tangled mat.&#xD;
These plants are Dioecious and this one had male flowers.&#xD;
Spotted in a sclerophyll bush - part of the Cranbourne Botanical Gardens. Soil might have been a little sandy.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Hypolaena fastigiata</category>
      <category>tag~flower-male</category>
      <category>tag~plant</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54fb9b20ed2a890393000062.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:43:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thelymitra ixioides s.l.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54fa47fced2a89097e00063d.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Tall plant with beautiful blue flowers with purplish tinge ot the outer surface of sepals. Yellow pollinia was visible at the tip of the column. Stigmatic surface showed a dense tuft of white hairs. Leaves were erect and narrow ( not seen here).&#xD;
Spotted in semi-shade in a reserve with eucalypts and natives - dry sclerophyll forest.&#xD;
The flowers bloom in October and November.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Thelymitra ixioides s.l.</category>
      <category>tag~orchid</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54fa47fced2a89097e00063d.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:36:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrenosoma queenslandi</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f98f22ed2a89097e00055d.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This black robber fly was about 15 mm long. The thorax was flat along the midline and symmetrically lumpy on either side. Eyes were large and facing upwards. Stiff white bristles seen between the eyes and on the face. Legs also had stiff white setae. Wings were dark and folded over the abdomen which had white spots on the lateral aspects of some of the tergites.&#xD;
Spotted flying around dried logs ( Langwarrin Flora &amp; Fauna Reserve).&#xD;
Synonym: Laphria maura &#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Andrenosoma queenslandi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f98f22ed2a89097e00055d.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 11:27:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydnum repandum</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f988f6ed2a89097e00054b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Pic 1 shows the underside of the cap of this thick white fungus. The fertile surface showed closely packed white "teeth" instead of gills or pores. The teeth were decurrent ( running down the stem) -pic 4. The young fruiting bodies were growing in a clump with some of their thick white stipes fused together. The caps were a pale orange, distorted by mutual pressure and showed in-rolled margins. The stem turned a beautiful orange when bruised or cut.&#xD;
Growing on a damp eucalyptus forest floor, among leaf and wood debris.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Hydnum repandum</category>
      <category>tag~fungi</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f988f6ed2a89097e00054b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 11:01:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Periclystus circuiter</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f96b82ed2a89097e000505.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This fantastic antlion looked like many other things ( a piece of moulted reptilian skin, an abandoned cobweb with trapped insects and even dried-up bird dropping.) as it clung to a dried twig. Pic 4 is a dorsal view and Pic 5 from the underside showing a dark abdomen. The head, thorax and abdomen were dark with the last abdominal segments showing some yellow. Antennae were short with slightly curved tips. The spectacular wings looked like lace with dark patterns of black and brown. When in flight, the frames of the wings were hardly visible, showing flashes of dark spatters. Body length (including long fore-wings and antennae) would have been about 50 mm.&#xD;
Spotted on a dry Goodenia plant in a nature reserve ( Wick's) &#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Periclystus circuiter</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f96b82ed2a89097e000505.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 08:55:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microtis arenaria</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f9638bed2a89097e0004f4.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Called the "Notched Onion-orchid" this orchid plant was about 50 cm high. I could see a single long sheath like leaf from the centre of which rose a slender green stem bearing a spike of flowers. &#xD;
The central sepal was hooded covering the petals. Lateral sepals curled backwards. The lip was bilobed with a slightly wavy margin.&#xD;
At first this plant looked like it had unopened buds- the flowers were so small and are not conspicuous. They are apparently scented ! &#xD;
Spotted in semi-shade. </description>
      <category>id~Microtis arenaria</category>
      <category>tag~orchid</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f9638bed2a89097e0004f4.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 08:27:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f914b2ed2a89097e000470.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>The main picture shows a dissected gall exposing larvae at various stages of development with pale pink segmented bodies and a few eggs (pic 4). The galls were about 3 to 4 mm wide, shiny and green with knobbly tips. They seemed to arise from tips of leaflets (pinnules) and involved most of the leaflet (pic 2). Several of these galls were seen on the pinnae. Pic 4 shows a developing gall on a leaflet. The larvae seemed to have segments differentiated into thoracic and abdominal segments and there appeared to be three pairs of legs (pic 6) suggesting that these were mature and close to pupation ?. I assume these are midge galls and would greatly appreciate confirmation.&#xD;
- ? Austroacacidiplosis botrycephalae&#xD;
Spotted on Black Wattle (Acacia mearnsii) in a nature reserve ( Glenfern Valley Bushland Reserve)&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~acacia</category>
      <category>tag~galls</category>
      <category>tag~midge</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f914b2ed2a89097e000470.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 02:45:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opisthoscelis beardsleyi</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f599afed2a8945a1000543.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These sub-conical galls with apical holes are female galls of a gall inducing scale insect. The female galls showed enlarged leaf glands. Some leaves also showed small cylindrical galls with apical openings- these were the males of the same species of scale insect (pic 3). Pic 2 shows galls of both sexes on the one leaf. &#xD;
The underside of the leaf showed slight discolouration and minimal waxy bloom (pic 4).&#xD;
Spotted on juvenile leaves of a eucalyptus tree (species unknown) in a nature reserve.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Opisthoscelis beardsleyi</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <category>tag~scale-insect</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f599afed2a8945a1000543.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 11:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eremococcus turbinata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f55314ed2a8983c2000490.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A lobulated gall probably involving terminal leaf buds. the galls were green and red and glossy. they were small, about 5 to 7mm wide. A dissected dry gall ( pics 4 &amp; 5) showed thickened concentric layers of tissue. There was no sign of any life inside the gall.&#xD;
Spotted on a prickly tea-tree (Leptospermum juniperinum).&#xD;
This gall is formed by a scale insect of the genus Eremococcus. My thanks to L.Cook for the ID.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Eremococcus turbinata</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <category>tag~scale-insect</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f55314ed2a8983c2000490.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 06:22:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54eacddaed2a89ef270005e3.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Mountain Hickory Wattle Leaf Gall&#xD;
Several leaves of this young acacia shrub had circular to oval patches of thickened, firm, raised growths with brown encrustation on their pale convex surfaces (pics 1 to 3). The growths were concave on the underside with a outer circle of similar brown crust (pic 4). These patches did not occur in any particular part of the leaf - some involved the mid vein and others anywhere on the leaf lamina. A dissection of one of these structures revealed just thick tough plant tissue.&#xD;
Spotted on young Mountain Hickory Wattle ( Acacia obliquinervia) shrubs on Mt Donna Buang (1250 masl)&#xD;
Architect of gall unknown.</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54eacddaed2a89ef270005e3.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 06:51:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cornus capitata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e96b2eed2a8987b70005a0.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Beautiful, showy white flower heads on a medium-sized tree. the flower heads were on narrow upright stems bearing tight clusters of minute flowers with reduced petals ( pic 5). Each flower head had creamy white bracts - about 4 and sometimes 6. These bracts appeared green on younger flowerheads (pic 4) or tinged with pink (pic 3). Leaves had glossy upper surface.&#xD;
Spotted growing in a reserve in the Dandenong Ranges ( Wet Eucalyptus forest).</description>
      <category>id~Cornus capitata</category>
      <category>tag~exotic-plant</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e96b2eed2a8987b70005a0.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 05:37:50 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culama suffusca</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e878fced2a89d990000624.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This handsome male cossid moth was grey with fine black lines on wings. Some parts of the wings were tinged with a pale brown.The tufted grey thorax had two bands of black. Legs had thick setae and tarsi were banded.&#xD;
Spotted under bright lights near a national park.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Culama suffusca</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e878fced2a89d990000624.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 12:24:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diamma bicolor</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e1ddbded2a89d9900002e3.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This male "Blue Ant" wasp was of a moderate size-15 mm. It had black head, eyes, thorax and abdomen and short black antennae. The abdomen had 3 visible white markings on both dorsal and ventral aspects and perhaps a pair of small white patches at the waist. The anterior thoracic margin was also white. &#xD;
Wings were tinted and the leading edges appeared black and thickened. Femurs, tibiae and tarsi were brown.&#xD;
Spotted on tea-tree.</description>
      <category>id~Diamma bicolor</category>
      <category>tag~male-adult</category>
      <category>tag~wasp</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e1ddbded2a89d9900002e3.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 12:08:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Septobasidium clelandii</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e1b777ed2a8987b700021b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A highly branched black clump of fruiting bodies arising from stem galls. They were about 5 to 12 mm long and stretching out like large magnetised iron-filings.&#xD;
Spotted arising from stem galls (seen as thickened split lumps) on branches of tea-tree shrubs (Leptospermum sp.) in a reserve - Royal Botanic Gardens in Cranbourne.&#xD;
This fungus ( basidiomycota) is a parasite on the female gall inducing Eriococcid insect Callococcus leptospermi. &#xD;
Photo and description of this specimen can also be seen on Bruce Fuhrer's " A field guide to Australian Fungi".&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Septobasidium clelandii</category>
      <category>tag~fungus</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e1b777ed2a8987b700021b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 09:25:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brachystomatidae spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e1892ded2a89d990000262.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This was a very active fly about 5 or 6 mm long. Head and thorax were black and the thorax showed two faint thin white lines. The head had two short pointed black antennae that were either held straight up like horns (Pic 1) or slicked back. &#xD;
A long proboscis was out lapping up the nectar on the flower disc (pic 1). The abdomen was a raspberry red with faint white lines. The last segment was black and the two anterior to this were white. &#xD;
Legs were black and long. The wings were tinted black but plain.&#xD;
Tony Daley's (Insects of Tasmania) comment on this spotting : "Comes remarkably close to the female of Hardy's (1934) Apalocnemis sanguineus (Qld). That species has the wing dark suffusion more restricted basally. He mentions at the end of that description "a closely allied species" collected from Ringwood (Vic) which has "the wings suffused intensely over a larger area". Hardy (1934) : http://www.biodiversitylibrary.org/item/... Note that Hardy has that species in Empidinae but it is currently placed in Brachystomatidae." </description>
      <category>id~Brachystomatidae spp.</category>
      <category>tag~fly</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e1892ded2a89d990000262.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 06:07:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceratiomyxa fruitculosa</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e17521ed2a89d990000202.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Highly branched clumps of fruiting bodies of slime mold. The sporocarps, about 2 mm high, appeared to have a powdery surface which is presumably a phase that this slime mold undergoes.&#xD;
Seen on the underside of fallen twigs in a damp area - nature reserve.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Ceratiomyxa fruitculosa</category>
      <category>tag~slime-mould</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e17521ed2a89d990000202.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 04:42:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dasineura tomentosa</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e17017ed2a89d9900001f2.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Looking very much like small Camellia flower buds, these pea-sized growths could easily be mistaken for flower buds on the tea tree. They were globose, had scaly bract like outer growth and layers of soft sheaths within. They did not appear to have stalks and were seen on branches between nodes. &#xD;
 On cutting one of them open, I found at least two very small maggots at the base, not much over 1 mm in length. The inside of the gall was soft with white fibrous layers.&#xD;
Spotted on Coastal Tea Tree ( Leptospermum laevigatum) </description>
      <category>id~Dasineura tomentosa</category>
      <category>tag~midge</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e17017ed2a89d9900001f2.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 04:20:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eurispa vittata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e161eeed2a89d9900001c0.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This slender leaf beetle was about 10 mm long. Ihad heavily pitted elytra with black, cream and purple stripes. The elytra appear to be drawn out into short spines at the apices. &#xD;
The black thorax had a median ridge. Segmented antennae and the legs were black. &#xD;
The beetle was resting with its body along the axis of the plant, the purplish stripes merging well with the plant.&#xD;
Spotted on cutting grass (Gahnia grandis)&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Eurispa vittata</category>
      <category>tag~beetle</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e161eeed2a89d9900001c0.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 03:20:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entometa apicalis</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e15a0ded2a8987b700018b.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This downy caterpillar was about 25 mm long. It had a brown and cream blotchy appearance. First pictures displaying displeasure - raised and tucked in head to display black bands and erectile horns.  After about 20 min. the caterpillar had descended the branch and was resting with its body totally camouflaged against the branch (pic 4). Spotted on young eucalyptus tree - nature reserve ( Wicks)</description>
      <category>id~Entometa apicalis</category>
      <category>tag~caterpillar</category>
      <category>tag~larva</category>
      <category>tag~moth</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e15a0ded2a8987b700018b.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 02:46:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>