<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link href="https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/collections/galls_of_victoria/index.rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <title>Galls Of Victoria</title>
    <link>https://natureshare.org/items?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fcollections%2Fgalls_of_victoria%2Findex.json</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 leuba</copyright>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 22:34:22 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>jsonfeed-to-rss 3.0.3 (https://github.com/bcomnes/jsonfeed-to-rss#readme)</generator>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Schedotrioza spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2017%2F59cddf48ed2a89c0fd00005f.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These were attractive thin-walled urn-shaped galls that appeared to be about 10 to 12 mm tall. The apical openings through which the adults would have emerged had jagged edges which were a deep pink. This colour bled into the pale green bodies and bases of the galls.&#xD;
Spotted on the upper surface of eucalyptus leaves - Gum tree species not known.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Schedotrioza spp.</category>
      <category>tag~leaf-gall</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2017/59cddf48ed2a89c0fd00005f.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 05:57:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schedotrioza spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2016%2F569c318ced2a89f5e100002e.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These small dry star-bursts of psyllid galls looked like rusted metal flowers stuck to the upper surfaces of gum leaves. These eruptions looked a lot "neater" than some of the galls induced by these little hemipterans.&#xD;
Spotted on what looked like Silver-leaf Stringy Bark ( E.cinerea) in a reserve.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Schedotrioza spp.</category>
      <category>tag~galls</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2016/569c318ced2a89f5e100002e.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:39:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trioza spp.</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F562460a6ed2a89401600acaa.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>This eucalyptus tree with slightly pendulous branches and small clusters of creamy white flowers had delicate young leaves with their tips curled into thick cups. These cups appeared to have a membranous pale or brown lid (pic 5). Some of these cups had ants clustering around them as in pic 4. On opening one of these lidded "cups', I found a 3 mm psyllid nymph with small red wide-set eyes, orange thorax and green abdomen. Wings buds were dark with a white substance stuck to them. The tree had several young leaves with these galls.&#xD;
Spotted on a box gum ( ? Eucalyptus microcarpa) in a bushland reserve.&#xD;
I am not sure of the relationship between the ants and this species of psyllid. The gall-forming behaviour seems similar to Trioza species of psyllid. &#xD;
My thanks to Ken Walker for confirming that this is Trioza ( species not known).&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Trioza spp.</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/562460a6ed2a89401600acaa.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 03:16:54 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanyscelis maculata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F551d27d0ed2a89daf20000c8.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These are scale insect galls seen on the adaxial side of the leaf . The broad-based conical outgrowths are female galls. There were two of these, one at the base of the leaf base and another along the main vein. the gall was purplish and had a ring near the base. One of the galls showed two openings and the other a single smooth circular orifice. Also on the leaf surface were many upright tubular structures with apical openings with crenulated margins. These were male galls and they were tinged red.&#xD;
Spotted on a eucalyptus tree - ? species. Nature reserve.&#xD;
My thanks to Dr L.Cook for confirming genus and identifying the species.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Tanyscelis maculata</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <category>tag~scale-insect</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/551d27d0ed2a89daf20000c8.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 11:28:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f914b2ed2a89097e000470.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>The main picture shows a dissected gall exposing larvae at various stages of development with pale pink segmented bodies and a few eggs (pic 4). The galls were about 3 to 4 mm wide, shiny and green with knobbly tips. They seemed to arise from tips of leaflets (pinnules) and involved most of the leaflet (pic 2). Several of these galls were seen on the pinnae. Pic 4 shows a developing gall on a leaflet. The larvae seemed to have segments differentiated into thoracic and abdominal segments and there appeared to be three pairs of legs (pic 6) suggesting that these were mature and close to pupation ?. I assume these are midge galls and would greatly appreciate confirmation.&#xD;
- ? Austroacacidiplosis botrycephalae&#xD;
Spotted on Black Wattle (Acacia mearnsii) in a nature reserve ( Glenfern Valley Bushland Reserve)&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~acacia</category>
      <category>tag~galls</category>
      <category>tag~midge</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f914b2ed2a89097e000470.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 02:45:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opisthoscelis beardsleyi</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f599afed2a8945a1000543.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>These sub-conical galls with apical holes are female galls of a gall inducing scale insect. The female galls showed enlarged leaf glands. Some leaves also showed small cylindrical galls with apical openings- these were the males of the same species of scale insect (pic 3). Pic 2 shows galls of both sexes on the one leaf. &#xD;
The underside of the leaf showed slight discolouration and minimal waxy bloom (pic 4).&#xD;
Spotted on juvenile leaves of a eucalyptus tree (species unknown) in a nature reserve.&#xD;
&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Opisthoscelis beardsleyi</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <category>tag~scale-insect</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f599afed2a8945a1000543.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 11:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eremococcus turbinata</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54f55314ed2a8983c2000490.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>A lobulated gall probably involving terminal leaf buds. the galls were green and red and glossy. they were small, about 5 to 7mm wide. A dissected dry gall ( pics 4 &amp; 5) showed thickened concentric layers of tissue. There was no sign of any life inside the gall.&#xD;
Spotted on a prickly tea-tree (Leptospermum juniperinum).&#xD;
This gall is formed by a scale insect of the genus Eremococcus. My thanks to L.Cook for the ID.&#xD;
</description>
      <category>id~Eremococcus turbinata</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <category>tag~scale-insect</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54f55314ed2a8983c2000490.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 06:22:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidentified</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54eacddaed2a89ef270005e3.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Mountain Hickory Wattle Leaf Gall&#xD;
Several leaves of this young acacia shrub had circular to oval patches of thickened, firm, raised growths with brown encrustation on their pale convex surfaces (pics 1 to 3). The growths were concave on the underside with a outer circle of similar brown crust (pic 4). These patches did not occur in any particular part of the leaf - some involved the mid vein and others anywhere on the leaf lamina. A dissection of one of these structures revealed just thick tough plant tissue.&#xD;
Spotted on young Mountain Hickory Wattle ( Acacia obliquinervia) shrubs on Mt Donna Buang (1250 masl)&#xD;
Architect of gall unknown.</description>
      <category>id~Unidentified</category>
      <category>tag~gall</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54eacddaed2a89ef270005e3.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 06:51:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dasineura tomentosa</title>
      <link>https://natureshare.org/item?i=https%3A%2F%2Ffiles.natureshare.org%2Fleuba%2Fitems%2Fns%2F2015%2F54e17017ed2a89d9900001f2.yaml</link>
      <dc:creator>leuba</dc:creator>
      <description>Looking very much like small Camellia flower buds, these pea-sized growths could easily be mistaken for flower buds on the tea tree. They were globose, had scaly bract like outer growth and layers of soft sheaths within. They did not appear to have stalks and were seen on branches between nodes. &#xD;
 On cutting one of them open, I found at least two very small maggots at the base, not much over 1 mm in length. The inside of the gall was soft with white fibrous layers.&#xD;
Spotted on Coastal Tea Tree ( Leptospermum laevigatum) </description>
      <category>id~Dasineura tomentosa</category>
      <category>tag~midge</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://files.natureshare.org/leuba/items/ns/2015/54e17017ed2a89d9900001f2.yaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 04:20:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>